<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulation on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Vellum</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-vellum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-vellum/</guid>
      <description>General Vellum is a simulation framework that uses an extended Position Based Dynamics approach. It can be used to create many different things including cloth, hair, softbodies, balloons, and grains. The main advantage of a Position Based Approach is its controllability, stability, and ability to produce believable results quickly.
Graph Coloring  Graph Coloring  Graph coloring is a process where the primitives are segmented into non overlapping sets, where no set shares points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Axiom</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-axiom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-axiom/</guid>
      <description>s 28.42
Axiom Solver  Axiom &amp;gt; Main &amp;gt; Solver  Mode  Traditional  Traditional follows the exact steps of used by most fluid solvers   Reflection  Reflection is good at conserving energy in the sim, swirling motion will last longer.   Reflection Single Step  Less accurate but faster version of reflection (Default) Really no need to change from this     Division Size  Voxel div size, lower value means higher resolution   Voxels  Starting number of voxels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - FLIP</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-flip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-flip/</guid>
      <description>FLIP in SOP Container  FLIP container Creates a domain for a SOP FLIP fluid simulation.  SideFx docs  This node creates and initializes a SOP particle fluid domain. The Particle Separation parameter controls the domain’s resolution, but also the number of particles and voxels, and the resolution of collision objects.       Boundary  FLIP boundary
Creates a surface or density VDB for sourcing or deleting SOP FLIP fluid particles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>