<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unreal Engine on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal-engine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unreal Engine on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:24:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Snippets</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:24:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_snippets/</guid>
      <description>Trigger sequence with key  Lets add something to animate  We will add a simple cube   Create a sequence  In the top bar click Cinematics &amp;gt; Add Level Sequence  Or in the content browser RMB click &amp;gt; Animation &amp;gt; Level Sequence  Note: that if you do it this way you have to manually drag it to the viewport aswell     If the sequence is not open double click to open in the Sequencer With the sequence selected in the world outliner, in the details panel under the section &amp;ldquo;Playback&amp;rdquo; make sure that:  &amp;ldquo;Playback&amp;rdquo; is set to &amp;ldquo;Dont Loop&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Pause at End&amp;rdquo; is enabled   Select the object you want to animate in the world outliner and drag and drop in the sequencer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Communication</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_communication/</guid>
      <description>Below are som notes from a really good video on blueprint communication by Zak Parrish
Blueprint Communications | Live Training | Unreal Engine
Intro  A way for separate individual obejcts to talk to each other Useful for:  Broadcasting an event to a number of listeners Telling a specfic object to do something Quering another object   UE4 has no way to just &amp;ldquo;send a broad signal to everyone&amp;rdquo;  Trivia: had it in UE2, but it wasn’t very efficient   Communication will always involve the following:  A Sending Blueprint At least one Receiving Blueprint   Communication will always require a reference at some point  The Sender or Receiver has to become aware of the other   All Blueprint communication is 1-way  Blueprints can send data back and forth, but it requires both Blueprints to set up their own individual paths of communication Queries are possible, but are initiated by the Sender (still 1-way)    Types of communication  3 primary Blueprint communication Methods  Direct Communication Blueprint Interface message calls Event Dispatchers    When to use  Flow of communication  Is the sender pushing the data to the reciever?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:53:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>General Tips  System Units  UE uses centimeter (1 UE unit = 1cm)   Copy assets (as text)  If you select some static meshes and Ctrl C you save the selected assets, their translation etc to the clipboard You can then paste the data to a text editor. This data can the be Ctrl V in Unreal editor to &amp;ldquo;replace&amp;rdquo; the actors.   Anti-Aliasing  Project Settings &amp;gt; Engine &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt; Default Settings &amp;gt; Anti-Aliasing Method    Naming Convention Using a good naming convention is important to make the project more efficient to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Getting started</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Below are some notes from Getting Started in Unreal Engine
Install First we click the plus icon and select the version. When we click the install button we get a promt to choose instasll location. Here we can click the options button to choose we we want to include. If we know we are not interested in some of the target platforms we can uncheck them to avoid to have to download and install that data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>