<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unreal on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unreal on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>65 Mustang Fastback - 01</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/mustang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/mustang/</guid>
      <description>This project is a mix of Houdini &amp;amp; Unreal. The vehicle and cameras were animated in Houdini. The Dust sim was also done in Houdini using Axiom. The scene is lit by a quite lowrez HDRI, that was also used as a cheap environment. The ground is basically a plane with a Megascans texture. I did not want to do to much with the environment since the focus was on the animation workflow between Houdini and Unreral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pet Roadeo</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/pet-roadeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/pet-roadeo/</guid>
      <description>Houdini ♥️ Unreal
The aim with this project was to explore the workflow between Houdini and Unreal with the main focus on environment building, character &amp;amp; camera animation. I wanted the animation to be shaky, rough and give the feeling of speed.
I also had some software specific aims
 Houdini  KineFX  I wanted to explore rigging in KineFX (the procedural rigging toolset in Houdini) More specifically I wanted to learn how to create KineFX rig HDAs Explore how one rig HDA can drive another Create camera HDA for more quick camera animation   Scripting  Write a custom exporter to export a rig HDA to Unreal sequencer Write a custom exporter for camera animation to Unreal and sequencer     Unreal  General  As I am relatively new to Unreal just starting to use it to produce animation Get to know  Sequencer Movie render queue OCIO workflow     Scripting  Camera &amp;amp; object animation importer      This is a part of an ongoing personal project, so the assets are evolved over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego - Chappie</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/lego-chappie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/lego-chappie/</guid>
      <description>The model was animated using mocap retargeting with KineFX in Houdini. The animation (both the character and cameras) was then exported to a custom format and imported to Unreal Engine 5.3 using pipeline tools that I am developing. The sequence was rendered using the Path Tracer in UE and comped and graded in DaVinci Resolve.
  Houdini project. Exploring KineFX (procedural rigging and animation framework), rigid body dynamics and Solaris (scene building, layout, lighting, and rendering tools based on the USD framework)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>