<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Houdini Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-houdini-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-houdini-engine/</guid>
      <description>Install  Browse to the SideFX houdini engine dir  SideFX directory  C:\Program Files\Side Effects Software\Houdini Engine\Unreal Here you will find the engine for each of the houdini versions you have installed  19.5.403 19.5.303 etc&amp;hellip;   And inside each houdini version you will find a houdini engine plugin for each of the unreal engine versions.  5.0 4.27     Copy Houdini Engine dir  Find the version that matches your Houdini install and the UE engine Ctrl + C the HoudiniEngine directory     Browse to the Unreal plugin dir  Unreal engine version directory  C:\Program Files\Epic Games\UE_5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Misc</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-misc/</guid>
      <description>Tips UI  Selection  Box Select  Hold Ctrl + Alt + LMB clcik and drag      Material Graph  Reroute  You can add a reroute node by double clicking the connection line   Debug nodes  You can use the debug nodes under Debug to visually debug values. Lets say that you want to view the object bounds you can connect the output of an Object Bounds node to an Debug Float 3 node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Heightfield</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-heightfield/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 14:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-heightfield/</guid>
      <description>hf_tests_01.hiplcSome sample setups using hf wrangle </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Raytraced Lighting</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-raytraced-lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-raytraced-lighting/</guid>
      <description>Settings  Project Settings  Engine &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt;  Global Illumination &amp;gt;  Dynamic Global Illumination Method : Lumen   Reflections &amp;gt;  Reflection Method : Lumen Reflection Capture Resolution : 2048   Lumen &amp;gt;  Use Hardware Raytracing when available : On   Hardware Raytracing &amp;gt;  Support Hardware Raytracing : On  Note! Hardware Ray Tracing requires enabling skin cache. You will be promted to enable skin cache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Lumen</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-lumen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-lumen/</guid>
      <description>Lumen General Info  Surface Cache  Lumen generates an automatic parameterization of the nearby scene surfaces called the Surface Cache It is used to quickly look up lighting at ray hit points in the scene Lumen the captures the material properties for each mesh from multiple angles. These capture positions called cards are generated offline for each mesh   Screen Tracing  Lumen features trace rays against the screen first Before moving on to a more reliable method, if no hit is found or the ray passes behind a surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Movie Render Queue</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-movie-render-queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-movie-render-queue/</guid>
      <description>Movie Render Queue Config Before rendering any sequences loaded in the queue, you will need to configure the settings you want to use. There are a wide variety of settings that can be adjusted, such as output format, filename, and anti-aliasing settings.
 Settings
With the Settings options, you can specify additional configurable items to use when rendering the final output image.  Anti-aliasing  Controls the number of samples and sample types used when rendering out the final images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Python &amp; PySide2</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-python-pyside2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:03:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-python-pyside2/</guid>
      <description>Python plugin Enable the plugins you wish to use. There might be more scripting modules under the scripting tab depending on what you have installed and what you wish to be able to modify with python.
 Edit &amp;gt; Plugins &amp;gt; Scripting &amp;gt;  Editor Scripting Utilities Python Editor Script Plugin Sequencer Scripting etc &amp;hellip;    Developer Mode The developer mode will enable extra warnings eg for deprecated code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Life - 01</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/still-life-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/still-life-01/</guid>
      <description>Animated and rendered in Houdini</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vellum fluid - 01</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/vellum-fluid-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/vellum-fluid-01/</guid>
      <description>Animated and rendered in Houdini</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vellum grains - 01</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/vellum-grains-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/vellum-grains-01/</guid>
      <description>   Animated and rendered in Houdini
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</guid>
      <description>PBR  Base Color  Real world materials are not darker than 20 srgb or brighter than 240 srgb Rough surfaces have a higher minimun, around 50 srgb Out of range values will not light correctly, so staying in range is critical On a non-metallic material this controls the diffuse  On a metallic material this controls the specular On a metallic material the diffuse is black     Specular  A multiplier for the direct and indirect specular lighting Defining the reflectivity when looking straight at the surface Non-metal surfaces reflects about 4% of the light Specular value:  0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - LOPS &amp; USD</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-lops-usd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:09:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-lops-usd/</guid>
      <description>Solaris is the umbrella name for Houdini’s scene building, layout, lighting, and rendering tools based on the Universal Scene Description (USD) framework. LOP (lighting operator) nodes generate USD describing characters, props, lighting, and rendering.
Tips Lighting  Automatic headlight Creation  The default behaviour when there are no lights present in the scene is to create a default headlight. To disable the default light uncheck the following checkbox
Karma render settings (node) &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt; Geometry and Shading &amp;gt; Shading &amp;gt; Automatic Headlight Creation : Disable    Python Scene Graph Tree Lets select some prims in the Scene Graph Tree using Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego - Cars</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/lego-cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/lego-cars/</guid>
      <description>Music: Bjork by Podington Bear is licensed under a Attribution-NonCommercial 3.0 International License.
Animated and rendered in Houdini
Modeled in Bricklink Studio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego - Chappie</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/lego-chappie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/lego-chappie/</guid>
      <description>Lego model from: Mecabricks
Mocap from: Mixamo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCIO - Python</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ocio-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:18:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ocio-python/</guid>
      <description>I am writing a tool for Houdini that can create, save and apply color themes to color ramp parameters. In this project I needed to convert between color spaces. There are many ways to do this, but this led me to start exploring OCIO using Python. Below is a snippet that changes the color space of a list of rgb values from srgb to linear srgb.
 First I activate the venv into which I want to install OCIO Then I run pip install opencolorio With the package installed make sure that your IDE can access the package We also need to download a OCIO configuration file from here  import osimport PyOpenColorIO as OCIOdef apply_rgb(rgb, src_space, dst_space):try:config = OCIO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Cinematics</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-cinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:47:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-cinematics/</guid>
      <description>General Tips Camera  Perspective &amp;amp; Camera views  When you are animating a camera it can be nice to use a 2 pane view (cam and persp) setup. Pane setup  3dview (top left corner) &amp;gt; layouts &amp;gt; Two Panes (side by side) Set the cine camera view to use Cinematic Viewport  When a view is set to use the cinematic viewport you get a menu on the top right to set a number of overlays (grid, crosshair, action safe etc)     Cinematic Control  On the pane that you will use as a perspective camera, disable allow cinematic control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</guid>
      <description>Settings Configuration files The UE5 docs on configuration files
A tips &amp;amp; tricks video of setting up configuration files
 Invert Middle Mouse Pan
To pan the viewport I like to invert the middle mouse pan.  You can do this on a per project basis using the ui:  Edit &amp;gt; Editor Preferences &amp;gt; Level Editor &amp;gt; Viewports &amp;gt; Invert Middle Mouse Pan : On
Note this will only be set for the project   To invert the middle mouse pan on all new projects  Open the config directory of the engine version you want to edit  The path is something like C:\Program Files\Epic Games\UE_5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Snippets</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:24:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Misc  Enable Input  By default the key input is disabled in the standard template.  This is why we need to enable Input in the BeginPlay event   In a level blueprint we do not need to do this   Consume Keyboard event  By default a keyboard event has the property &amp;ldquo;Consume&amp;rdquo; enabled  if it is enabled it will prevent actors with a lower priority to handle the input     Logic Sequence (Flow Control)  If you want to call n number of functions from one input you can use the &amp;ldquo;Sequence&amp;rdquo; (Flow Control) node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Communication</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-communication/</guid>
      <description>Below are som notes from a really good video on blueprint communication by Zak Parrish
Blueprint Communications | Live Training | Unreal Engine
Intro  A way for separate individual obejcts to talk to each other Useful for:  Broadcasting an event to a number of listeners Telling a specfic object to do something Quering another object   UE4 has no way to just &amp;ldquo;send a broad signal to everyone&amp;rdquo;  Trivia: had it in UE2, but it wasn’t very efficient   Communication will always involve the following:  A Sending Blueprint At least one Receiving Blueprint   Communication will always require a reference at some point  The Sender or Receiver has to become aware of the other   All Blueprint communication is 1-way  Blueprints can send data back and forth, but it requires both Blueprints to set up their own individual paths of communication Queries are possible, but are initiated by the Sender (still 1-way)    Types of communication  3 primary Blueprint communication Methods  Direct Communication Blueprint Interface message calls Event Dispatchers    When to use  Flow of communication  Is the sender pushing the data to the reciever?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:53:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>General Tips  System Units  UE uses centimeter (1 UE unit = 1cm)   Copy assets (as text)  If you select some static meshes and Ctrl C you save the selected assets, their translation etc to the clipboard You can then paste the data to a text editor. This data can the be Ctrl V in Unreal editor to &amp;ldquo;replace&amp;rdquo; the actors.   Anti-Aliasing  Project Settings &amp;gt; Engine &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt; Default Settings &amp;gt; Anti-Aliasing Method    Naming Convention Using a good naming convention is important to make the project more efficient to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Getting started</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Below are some notes from Getting Started in Unreal Engine
Install First we click the plus icon and select the version. When we click the install button we get a promt to choose instasll location. Here we can click the options button to choose we we want to include. If we know we are not interested in some of the target platforms we can uncheck them to avoid to have to download and install that data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - KineFX</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-kinefx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:40:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-kinefx/</guid>
      <description>Capture Biharmonic Capture  Create Geometry node and step in Add Geo with sufficient resolution to allow for nice deformation (this is the geo we will capture) Add a Skeleton node and add joints. Append a Bone Capture Lines node to the skeleton node. Then we need to create a &amp;ldquo;Tet-mesh&amp;rdquo; of the geo we want to capture. This can be done in two different wways. We can either use a Tet Embed node or use a Remesh node to remesh and use a Tet Conform node to create a Tet-mesh based on the triangles created by the remesh node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equilateral</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/equilateral/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 16:13:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/equilateral/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glambot</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/glambot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/glambot/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Animation</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-animation/</guid>
      <description>Animation Editor Or graph editor in Maya speek.
 Set Keyframe : Alt LMB (click the parm) Delete Keyframe : Ctrl LMB (click the parm)  It will leave the current value (of the animation curve as) a static value   Reset to Default : Ctrl MMB (click the parm) Open Animation Editor : Shift LMB (click the parm) Edit Channel Properties : Select the channel, with the mouse pointer over the animation editor press Alt E  Or RMB click the channel &amp;gt; Channels &amp;gt; Channels Properties It is in this widget you can set how the curve will extrapolate before &amp;amp; after the keyframes    Copy/Paste Keyframes  Shift LMB click the parm to open the animation editor Select the keyframes and Ctrl C to copy Shift LMB click the parm that you want to paste to  This will open up the animation editor, with the channel selected in the channel list   Ctrl V paste the keyframes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Crowd</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-crowd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-crowd/</guid>
      <description>Houdini 18 crowd docs
Theese notes are based on the excellent tutorial by Mikael Pettersen, a little bit of CGWiki and random bits of information I stumble up on.
Minimal Setup Lets setup a minimal but &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; crowd.
 First create some geo, bones and capture the geometry. Then create a subnet to house all the parts we created in the previous step, This is our character rig. Create a new Geometry node and dive in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petbot</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/petbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/petbot/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Boxcutter</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-boxcutter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:53:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-boxcutter/</guid>
      <description>Boxcutter official docs
Shortcuts  Enable box cutter : Alt W (Will cycle hardpos if available) BoxCutter pie menu : D BoxCutter popup menu : Ctrl D  Tips Navigation When you have Maya style navigation set up this there is an option to preserve Alt and RMB keys.
 Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Add-ons &amp;gt; BoxCutter &amp;gt; Keymap &amp;gt;  Preserve Alt Preserve RMB    Cutters Linebox When you use the box shape there is an option called linebox that allows you to easily create Wedge shaped cuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Hard Ops</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-hardops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:53:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-hardops/</guid>
      <description>Hard Ops official docs
Shortcuts  Hops Menu : Q Bevel Helper : Ctrl Shift B  Object Mode Operations  Operations  Smart Apply  LMB : Smart apply modifiers (kkeps last bevel and weighted normal) Shift LMB Smart apply duplicate (With clear last bevel and weighted normal)      Edit Mode Curve/Extract  Curve/Extract  LMB : Converts edge to curve. Shift LMB : Converts selection to plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Modifiers</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:24:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modifiers/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers General  Here is the Blender modifier docs Apply all modifiers  Object &amp;gt; Convert to &amp;gt; Mesh from Curve/Meta/Surf/Text   Copy Modifiers  Note that we need the Copy Attributes Menu (Interface) add-on installed Select all the objects to copy the modifier to Lastly select the object with the modifiers to copy Ctrl C &amp;gt; Copy Modifiers    Vertex groups  How to create a vertex group  Go into edit mode of the mesh you want to add the group to Click the Object Data Properties Expand the Vertex Groups area Click the + button, and optionally name the group Use the Weights slider (or enter numerically) to specify the weight to be added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Modeling</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 16:27:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers General Gotchas Non-uniform object scale
If an object has non-uniform scale you can run into errors when doing operation on the mesh (edit mode). This is because the object scale is taken into account when the mesh is edited. For instance, we have a cube object with an x-scale of .1 (in object mode) and the verts (in edit mode) are scaled to compensate for this (x-scale 10) resulting in a cube that looks uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Intro</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 16:27:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-intro/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers It is finally time to start exploring Blender. I have had this on my todo list for a long time but there were alot of other things to focus on first.
Here is a nice Blender Fundamentals 2.8 playlist
Config The blender config is located here:
C:\Users\your_name\AppData\Roaming\Blender Foundation\Blender\2.83
To reset all config simply rename or delete the folder (the version you want to reset)
Regions Every Editor in Blender is divided into Regions (docs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bot 20</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/the-bot-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/the-bot-20/</guid>
      <description>  --  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoodie</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/hoodie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/hoodie/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocap Dance</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/mocap-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/mocap-dance/</guid>
      <description>     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini 18 - Sparse pyro</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-18-sparse-pyro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 21:17:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-18-sparse-pyro/</guid>
      <description>Some notes on using the sparse pyro solver taken while watching Steven Knippings excellent Volumes III v2.0
Source points Popnet Setup a particle sim that we will use as source for our smoke sim.
Point Wrangle Lets append a point wrangle to the particles. We will use the normailzed age to drive the density of the particles. We will use a ramp parameter and use the normalized age to drive the ramp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substance Painter - notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/substanc-painter-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 20:26:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/substanc-painter-notes/</guid>
      <description>Material sets &amp;amp; ID Maps Material set (Maya) or shop_materialpath (Houdini). To make it easier to paint it can be good to organize the model using 2 separate models (of the same model) but where the materials are named and assigned differently. Lets say that we wish to separate a model into 3 different texture sets. &amp;ldquo;base&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;mid&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;top&amp;rdquo;. We create material called this and assigns them to the geo that we want to separate i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substance Designer - notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/substance-designer-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 20:26:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/substance-designer-notes/</guid>
      <description>Parameters Conditional Visibility  Boolean  input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;] input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;] == true !input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;] input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;] == false input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;] != true   Float  input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;] &amp;lt; 3 input[&amp;ldquo;param1&amp;rdquo;] == 2 input[&amp;ldquo;MyInput&amp;rdquo;].y &amp;lt; 3 input[&amp;ldquo;param1&amp;rdquo;] || input[&amp;ldquo;param2&amp;rdquo;] input[&amp;ldquo;param1&amp;rdquo;] &amp;gt; 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; input[&amp;ldquo;param2&amp;rdquo;] &amp;gt; 1    Tips UV  To view the UVs in the 2D view  3D view Scene &amp;gt; Display UVs in 2D view    UDIM If you import a mesh that only have one uv tile but this tile is not the 1001 udim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvelous Designer</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/marvelous-designer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 11:23:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/marvelous-designer/</guid>
      <description>Tips Right Click There are a lot of useful RMB contextual menus:
 Copy/paste multiple  If you select a pattern and press Cmd C and then Cmd V and RMB click you can use number of instances and the spacing. (The direction is decided by the direction you had when RMB clicked) This also works for Internal lines   Precise numerical movement  If you want to move a point, line pattern you can first start to drag and while holding LMB click RMB to get a popup menu where you can set a numerical value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluorescent</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/fluorescent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/fluorescent/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guided</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/guided/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/guided/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow - Tips</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/workflow-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:53:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/workflow-tips/</guid>
      <description>Here I will post (mildly) useful things that falls outside more specfic topics.
Git Bash Which which ffmpeg/c/Program Files/ImageMagick/ffmpegPython Web scraping  pip install requests-html  Imagemagick You can RMB click and choose Git Bash here (or any other console you want to use)
Resize In-place resizing
magick mogrify -resize 50% *.pngResize to a separate folder (make sure the folder exists)
magick mogrify -resize 50% -path ./DST *.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dodecahedron</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/dodecahedron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/dodecahedron/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raku</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/raku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/raku/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceramics</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/ceramics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/ceramics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domino</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/domino/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 13:45:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/domino/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - UV</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-uv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 11:33:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-uv/</guid>
      <description>Vieport display options Open the vieport display option dialog (press D over the viewport)
 Markers tab &amp;gt; Vertices &amp;gt; UV Overlap  Displays the overlap in red (in the UV view)    UV Flatten  Rectify  Add a uv flatten node Under the section Flattening Constraints &amp;gt; Rectify Group  type *      UV Layout Target Assignment (UDIM) To force specific primitives to a specific UDIM we can use a primitive attr to specify which one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - COPS</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-cops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 12:27:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-cops/</guid>
      <description>Preferences In the Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Compositing we can set how many threads we want to use for the cooking and the Tile Size of each chunk of the tiles that will be processed. We can also set the Resolution Limit. If we do a mosaic of 1 K images we can exceed this limit and that can lead to issues.
The turn of the thumbnails of each cop node we can disable view &amp;gt; Show Node Previews in the menubar of the cop network view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - TOPS</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-tops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 15:09:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-tops/</guid>
      <description>General TOP nodes define a workflow where data is fed into the network, turned into &amp;ldquo;work items&amp;rdquo; and manipulated by different nodes. Many nodes represent external processes that can be run on the local machine or a server farm.
File paths Most TOP nodes that do work let you specify input and/or output file paths. In TOPs, each scheduler node can specify a working directory. This is because different render farm software may use different shared network filesystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Python</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:56:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-python/</guid>
      <description>Here I will gather information that I find useful.
Environment variables Houdini uses environment variables for various purposes, such as defining paths (sets of directories in which Houdini looks for certain types of files), commonly used directories (such as $HFS, the install location of Houdini) and for obscure or highly technical settings.
See the list of environment variables in Houdini.
Inspect variables To print the value of an environment variable you can use the Houdini Python Shell:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - HDA</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-hda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 10:50:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-hda/</guid>
      <description>The notes below are based on info found in the Houdini docs as well as other sources.
Digital Asset For a really nice and streamlined workflow of creating HDA you can use the SideFx Labs Digital Asset RMB menu.
Preferences Before you create an HDA it is a good idea to configure the preferences. Below is the way I have setup my prefs, but that is depending on your workflow etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Python</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 14:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-python/</guid>
      <description>An old scripting guide can be found here
Python &amp;amp; Lua Historically FusionScript was Lua only, some methods that return multiple statements have a special Table() suffix variant to return the proper table for use in Python. As the Lua collection is a tuple, you will need to pass a dictionary to the API in many cases, even when it seems to be treated like a list. So each Value needs to have a key in the order of the entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Fusion</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:58:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-fusion/</guid>
      <description>Quick tips  Auto Save  Auto save (live save) is on by default and you might want to turn it off. DaVinci Resolve &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Project Save and Load &amp;gt; Save Settings &amp;gt; Live save   Bookmarks  You can add bookmarks with Ctrl + D Underlays can also function as bookmarks Also in 3 dot menu       Page      Edit Shift + 4   Fusion Shift + 5   Color Shift + 6    Viewers There are two viewers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Edit</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:12:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-edit/</guid>
      <description>Quick tips  Import png &amp;amp; jpeg as a sequence  By default it seems like exr will import as a sequence but jpeg and png as stills. If you want to import png &amp;amp; jpeg as sequences  On the media page, click on the &amp;ldquo;3 dot menu&amp;rdquo; in the Media Storage section (top left) Frame Display Mode &amp;gt; Sequence     Auto Save  Auto save (live save) is on by default and you might want to turn it off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/hugo-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/hugo-notes/</guid>
      <description>Creating/coding for the web is not my primarily focus but i think it is an important skill to have and will be increasingly so. As part of a 1 year program in business and marketing I did almost 20 years ago we had a short course in web development. The instructor insisted that we should use Dreamweaver (Macromedia at the time). I did not like it, I thought it hid the internal mechanics and I wanted to get closer to the actual language so I ended up writing everything in notepad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini 17 - Pyro</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-17-pyro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-17-pyro/</guid>
      <description>Add a geo to use as source and append a Pyro Source node to it. This node does not make the volume, it creates points.
Below are some lines form the docs The Pyro Source SOP converts its input geometry into points suitable for sourcing pyro and smoke simulations. This SOP adds specified attributes to the generated points, which can be rasterized and imported into desired DOP fields by the Volume Source node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/tunnel/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proc city 02</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/proc-city-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/proc-city-02/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bot</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/the-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/the-bot/</guid>
      <description>       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/ray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/ray/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Copco - Genuine parts</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/genuine-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/genuine-parts/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jet Set Pets</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/work/jetsetpets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 15:10:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/work/jetsetpets/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - VEX</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-vex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:45:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-vex/</guid>
      <description>Attributes Set attrib type info int pnt = addpoint(0,0);vector4 quat = quaternion(0);setpointattrib(0, &amp;#39;orient&amp;#39;, pnt, quat);setattribtypeinfo(0, &amp;#39;point&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;orient&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;quaternion&amp;#39;);Transform Quaternion  Quaternion to Euler  Specify the rotation order with the order integer. Use the constants defined in $HH/vex/include/math.h (for example, XFORM_XYZ) Note! You do not need to include math.h in a wrangle (like this: #include &amp;lt;math.h&amp;gt;) it is included by default. vector euler = degrees(quaterniontoeuler(p@orient, XFORM_XYZ));    Matrix  Get matrix components  You can use getcomp function&amp;hellip; getcomp(&amp;lt;matrix&amp;gt;m, int row, int column) &amp;hellip;but you can also access components using m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - VEX Flex</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-vex-flex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 13:45:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-vex-flex/</guid>
      <description>This is not really VEX flexing but I really liked that title :)
Trigonometry Rotation In an Unreal shader I was building I needed to &amp;ldquo;rotate back&amp;rdquo; some pixels in the normal map so that the normals was corrected when the uv for the texture sampling was rotated. The key is to use the inverted rotation to rotate back the R(U) and G(V) color values (per pixel) so that the map is corrected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flask SQLite dev</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/flask-sqlite-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/flask-sqlite-dev/</guid>
      <description>The database will contain materials, material types and surface properties.
  Material
 id name material type surface properties    Material type
 id name    Surface property
 id name     Installation create a project dir an cd into it.
create an environment
OSX python3 -m venv venvActivate the environment
. venv/bin/activateinstall flask
pip install FlaskThere is a regular SQLAlchemy package but flask-sqlalchemy is a flask specific extension that provides some useful defaults and helpers for flask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Misc</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 20:32:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-misc/</guid>
      <description>A collection of various Houdini related things that doesn´t fit anywhere else.
POP Birth Rate A good way to control the amount of particles being emitted is to keyframe the Const. Birt Rate (Birth tab) with values between 0 and 1. Then we can use the Scale Point Count by Area (Source tab) as a multiplier of points emitted.
Rest attribute If we want to store the position where the particle was spawned we can create a rest attribute to the geo that we use as source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PySide2 - Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/pyside2-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/pyside2-notes/</guid>
      <description>General Install PySide2 To install PySide2 (including Shiboken2 &amp;amp; Qt) make sure that we first activate our venv
pip install PySide2Hello World app Lets build a simple ui and run with sublimeText. Select the build system we just created and build Ctrl B
from PySide2 import QtCorefrom PySide2 import QtWidgetsfrom PySide2 import QtGuiimport sysfrom functools import partialclass HelloWidget(QtWidgets.QWidget):def __init__(self, parent=None):super(HelloWidget, self).__init__(parent)self.setGeometry(400, 400, 250, 50)self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python - General</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/python/</guid>
      <description>This assumes you are using Python 3. (I am also using Git Bash as my shell)
Venv Setup a virtual environment It is a good idea to install packages in virtual environment so that we do not clutter our main python install, and we can easily get rid of the packages if we want. First we need to create the virtual enveronment. Navigat to a folder where you want your venv and type cd into it and then run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SublimeText</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/sublime-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/sublime-text/</guid>
      <description>Misc Diff files  Diff two files  Make sure the files are in the &amp;ldquo;Folders&amp;rdquo; section  You can add folders to the project by dragging and dropping   Selct the first file, then Ctrl select the second RMB click &amp;gt; Diff Files&amp;hellip;   Only works with UTF-8 files  If you can not diff to files that should be &amp;ldquo;diffable&amp;rdquo; then you probably have some non-ascii characters A quick way to inspect teh file is to press &amp;ldquo;Ctrl F&amp;rdquo; then press &amp;ldquo;Alt R&amp;rdquo; to enable Regex mode  You can also click the regex button on the left most edge of the search input field   Then paste the regex [^\x00-\x7F] in the searc input field Press find    Search and replace # I wanted to change a H3 header (###) in a markdown file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>