<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blender on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/blender/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blender on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:53:41 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/blender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Boxcutter</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_boxcutter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:53:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_boxcutter/</guid>
      <description>Boxcutter official docs
Tips Navigation When you have Maya style navigation set up this there is an option to preserve Alt and RMB keys.
 Preserve Alt : &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Add-ons &amp;gt; BoxCutter &amp;gt; Keymap &amp;gt; Preserve Alt Preserve RMB : &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Add-ons &amp;gt; BoxCutter &amp;gt; Keymap &amp;gt; Preserve RMB  Cutters Linebox When you use the box shape there is an option called linebox that allows you to easily create Wedge shaped cuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Hard Ops</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_hardops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:53:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_hardops/</guid>
      <description>Hard Ops official docs
Tips Shortcuts  Hops Menu : Q Bevel Helper : Ctrl Shift B  ST3 Mesh Tools  Selection to Boolean : Create a boolean from the selected face.  Select the face(s) Q &amp;gt; ST3 Mesh Tools &amp;gt; Selection to Boolean LMB click once, you can now move the mouse to adjust the extrude depth. Press X to switch to setting the offset. Press X again to set the offset Pressing X again will cycle back to setting the extrude depth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Modifiers</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_modifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:24:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_modifiers/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers General  Here is the Blender modifier docs Apply all modifiers  Object &amp;gt; Convert to &amp;gt; Mesh from Curve/Meta/Surf/Text   Copy Modifiers  Note that we need the Copy Attributes Menu (Interface) add-on installed Select all the objects to copy the modifier to Lastly select the object with the modifiers to copy Ctrl C &amp;gt; Copy Modifiers    Vertex groups  How to create a vertex group  Go into edit mode of the mesh you want to add the group to Click the Object Data Properties Expand the Vertex Groups area Click the + button, and optionally name the group Use the Weights slider (or enter numerically) to specify the weight to be added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Modeling</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 16:27:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_modeling/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers General Gotchas Non-uniform object scale
If an object has non-uniform scale you can run into errors when doing operation on the mesh (edit mode). This is because the object scale is taken into account when the mesh is edited. For instance, we have a cube object with an x-scale of .1 (in object mode) and the verts (in edit mode) are scaled to compensate for this (x-scale 10) resulting in a cube that looks uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Intro</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 16:27:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender_intro/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers It is finally time to start exploring Blender. I have had this on my todo list for a long time but there were alot of other things to focus on first.
Here is a nice Blender Fundamentals 2.8 playlist
Config The blender config is located here:
C:\Users\your_name\AppData\Roaming\Blender Foundation\Blender\2.83To reset all config simply rename or delete the folder (the version you want to reset)
Regions Every Editor in Blender is divided into Regions (docs).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>