<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LOPS-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/lops-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LOPS-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:09:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/lops-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - LOPS &amp; USD</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-lops-usd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:09:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-lops-usd/</guid>
      <description>Solaris is the umbrella name for Houdini’s scene building, layout, lighting, and rendering tools based on the Universal Scene Description (USD) framework. LOP (lighting operator) nodes generate USD describing characters, props, lighting, and rendering.
Tips Instancer  Instancer  The hip file below ( karma_instancer_motionblur.hiplc ) contains a simple instancer setup SOP level  Prototype meshes  Create some meshes to use as prototypes Give each mesh a unique primitve name attrib, for instance &amp;ldquo;sphere&amp;rdquo; Create a path attrib to place them where you want them in the scene graph  we can do this with vex and base it on the name attrib: s@path = &amp;lsquo;/geo/meshes/&amp;lsquo;+s@name;     Target Points  Create some points Give them names (point attrib) that matches the name we gave to meshes  The point attrib name will be used to instance the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; geo       LOP level  SOP Create  Create an SOP Create node Dive in, and create an Object Merge and point to the SOP geo Solaris will use the path attrib to place the prims in the scene tree   Collection  Create a Collection node Give it a Collection Name: &amp;ldquo;my_collection&amp;rdquo; Remove the all text inside the Primitives textbox Write /geo/meshes/* in the Primitives textbox  what this means is that it will add all primitives below this primitive to the collection   Note: from the scene graph tree you can also drag and drop the &amp;ldquo;geo/meshes&amp;rdquo; that we brought in with the sop create.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>