<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DaVinci Resolve-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/davinci-resolve-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DaVinci Resolve-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/davinci-resolve-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Color</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-color/</guid>
      <description>Groups The color page allows you to group clips and grade the clips based on which group it belongs to. This is super handy!
 Grade car lights  Background  In this example we have a rendered sequence of a car and want to add a small glow to the lights. We have the rendered car as a layer On top of this we add a black/white mask of the lights (lets call the light masks)  Note if we want to edit the strength of the glow easily it is a good idea to have each light mask trimmed to the specific shot Meaning they are individual clips on the timeline that we can set blend mode and opacity per clip     Import media  Import the car sequence and add to a timeline (in the edit page) Import the light masks, add to the car timeline (on top of the car render) Make sure the align with the underlaying sequence (in time and shape)   Grade the lights  Create Groups  Switch to the color page In the topbar, make sure Clips is enabled (top left) and that Timeline is eanbled (top right) Underneath the monitor and nodegraph you can se the clips and underneath thjat the timeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Python</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 14:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-python/</guid>
      <description>An old scripting guide can be found here
Python &amp;amp; Lua Historically FusionScript was Lua only, some methods that return multiple statements have a special Table() suffix variant to return the proper table for use in Python. As the Lua collection is a tuple, you will need to pass a dictionary to the API in many cases, even when it seems to be treated like a list. So each Value needs to have a key in the order of the entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Fusion</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:58:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-fusion/</guid>
      <description>Quick tips  Auto Save  Auto save (live save) is on by default and you might want to turn it off. DaVinci Resolve &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Project Save and Load &amp;gt; Save Settings &amp;gt; Live save   Bookmarks  You can add bookmarks with Ctrl + D Underlays can also function as bookmarks Also in 3 dot menu       Page      Edit Shift + 4   Fusion Shift + 5   Color Shift + 6    Viewers There are two viewers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Edit</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:12:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci-resolve-edit/</guid>
      <description>Quick tips  Import png &amp;amp; jpeg as a sequence  By default it seems like exr will import as a sequence but jpeg and png as stills. If you want to import png &amp;amp; jpeg as sequences  On the media page, click on the &amp;ldquo;3 dot menu&amp;rdquo; in the Media Storage section (top left) Frame Display Mode &amp;gt; Sequence     Auto Save  Auto save (live save) is on by default and you might want to turn it off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>