<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tag on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/tag/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tag on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:56:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/tag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini Python notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_python_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:56:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_python_notes/</guid>
      <description>Here I will gather information that I find useful.
Environment variables Houdini uses environment variables for various purposes, such as defining paths (sets of directories in which Houdini looks for certain types of files), commonly used directories (such as $HFS, the install location of Houdini) and for obscure or highly technical settings.
See the list of environment variables in Houdini.
Inspect variables To print the value of an environment variable you can use the Houdini Python Shell:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - HDA</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_hda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 10:50:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_hda/</guid>
      <description>The notes below are based on info found in the Houdini docs as well as other sources.
Asset name The general form of an asset’s internal name is
[namespace::]node_name[::version]
The namespace and version are both optional. You can have a name with both a namespace and a version, or just a namespace, or just a version, or neither.
Namespaces The namespace identifier lets you name your assets without worrying about using the same name as a built-in Houdini node or as a third-party asset you might use someday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DaVinci Resolve - Fusion</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci_resolve_fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:58:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/davinci_resolve_fusion/</guid>
      <description>Create a fusion comp Timeline to fusion To &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; a clip from the edit page to the fusion page we set the playhead on the clip and switch over to the fusion page, This will give use 2 nodes the media in and media out
New Composition We can also create a new Fusion composition. Open up the media pool, RMB click in the content section of a bin and choose &amp;ldquo;New Fusion Composition&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>