<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Houdini-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/houdini-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Houdini-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:09:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/houdini-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - LOPS</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_lops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:09:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_lops/</guid>
      <description>Solaris is the umbrella name for Houdini’s scene building, layout, lighting, and rendering tools based on the Universal Scene Description (USD) framework. LOP (lighting operator) nodes generate USD describing characters, props, lighting, and rendering.
Nodes Rendering Camera Latlong cubemap in Karma
I needed to render out a cube map using Karma so this led me to dig deeper into lens shaders. Paul Ambrosiussen as well as Matt Estela
karma_lens_shader_01.hiplcLatlong / Polar CVEX Lens shader  Settings Applies renderer-specific geometry settings to geometry in the scene graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - KineFX</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_kinefx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:40:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_kinefx/</guid>
      <description>Capture Biharmonic Capture  Create Geometry node and step in Add Geo with sufficient resolution to allow for nice deformation (this is the geo we will capture) Add a Skeleton node and add joints. Append a Bone Capture Lines node to the skeleton node. Then we need to create a &amp;ldquo;Tet-mesh&amp;rdquo; of the geo we want to capture. This can be done in two different wways. We can either use a Tet Embed node or use a Remesh node to remesh and use a Tet Conform node to create a Tet-mesh based on the triangles created by the remesh node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Animation</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_animation/</guid>
      <description>Animation Editor Or graph editor in Maya speek.
 Set Keyframe : Alt LMB (click the parm) Delete Keyframe : Ctrl LMB (click the parm)  It will leave the current value (of the animation curve as) a static value   Reset to Default : Ctrl MMB (click the parm) Open Animation Editor : Shift LMB (click the parm) Edit Channel Properties : Select the channel, with the mouse pointer over the animation editor press Alt E  Or RMB click the channel &amp;gt; Channels &amp;gt; Channels Properties It is in this widget you can set how the curve will extrapolate before &amp;amp; after the keyframes    Copy/Paste Keyframes  Shift LMB click the parm to open the animation editor Select the keyframes and Ctrl C to copy Shift LMB click the parm that you want to paste to  This will open up the animation editor, with the channel selected in the channel list   Ctrl V paste the keyframes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Crowd</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_crowd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 14:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_crowd/</guid>
      <description>Houdini 18 crowd docs
Theese notes are based on the excellent tutorial by Mikael Pettersen, a little bit of CGWiki and random bits of information I stumble up on.
Minimal Setup Lets setup a minimal but &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; crowd.
 First create some geo, bones and capture the geometry. Then create a subnet to house all the parts we created in the previous step, This is our character rig. Create a new Geometry node and dive in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini 18 - Sparse pyro</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_18_sparse_pyro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 21:17:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_18_sparse_pyro/</guid>
      <description>Some notes on using the sparse pyro solver taken while watching Steven Knippings excellent Volumes III v2.0
Source points Popnet Setup a particle sim that we will use as source for our smoke sim.
Point Wrangle Lets append a point wrangle to the particles. We will use the normailzed age to drive the density of the particles. We will use a ramp parameter and use the normalized age to drive the ramp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - UV</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_uv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 11:33:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_uv/</guid>
      <description>Vieport display options Open the vieport display option dialog (press D over the viewport)
 Markers tab &amp;gt; Vertices &amp;gt; UV Overlap  Displays the overlap in red (in the UV view)    UV Layout Target Assignment (UDIM) To force specific primitives to a specific UDIM we can use a primitive attr to specify which one.
 Create a poly tube with end caps. Create groups for the top, btm and the &amp;ldquo;mid&amp;rdquo;  One way to do this is to use the group by normal for the top and btm and for the mid a group combine with &amp;ldquo;equals all but&amp;rdquo; the top and btm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Compositing</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_compositing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 12:27:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_compositing/</guid>
      <description>Preferences In the Edit &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Compositing we can set how many threads we want to use for the cooking and the Tile Size of each chunk of the tiles that will be processed. We can also set the Resolution Limit. If we do a mosaic of 1 K images we can exceed this limit and that can lead to issues.
The turn of the thumbnails of each cop node we can disable view &amp;gt; Show Node Previews in the menubar of the cop network view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - TOPS</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_tops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 15:09:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_tops/</guid>
      <description>TOP nodes define a workflow where data is fed into the network, turned into &amp;ldquo;work items&amp;rdquo; and manipulated by different nodes. Many nodes represent external processes that can be run on the local machine or a server farm.
Wedge geo variations Lets setup a TOP network to write out geo variations to disc. We will do this using a Wedge node.
Pull vs Push For each wedged attribute, you can use it to set a parameter on the render node in one of two ways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Python</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:56:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_python/</guid>
      <description>Here I will gather information that I find useful.
Environment variables Houdini uses environment variables for various purposes, such as defining paths (sets of directories in which Houdini looks for certain types of files), commonly used directories (such as $HFS, the install location of Houdini) and for obscure or highly technical settings.
See the list of environment variables in Houdini.
Inspect variables To print the value of an environment variable you can use the Houdini Python Shell:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - HDA</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-hda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 10:50:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini-hda/</guid>
      <description>The notes below are based on info found in the Houdini docs as well as other sources.
Digital Asset For a really nice and streamlined workflow of creating HDA you can use the SideFx Labs Digital Asset RMB menu.
Preferences Before you create an HDA it is a good idea to configure the preferences. Below is the way I have setup my prefs, but that is depending on your workflow etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini 17 - Pyro</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_17_pyro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 11:16:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_17_pyro/</guid>
      <description>Add a geo to use as source and append a Pyro Source node to it. This node does not make the volume, it creates points.
Below are some lines form the docs The Pyro Source SOP converts its input geometry into points suitable for sourcing pyro and smoke simulations. This SOP adds specified attributes to the generated points, which can be rasterized and imported into desired DOP fields by the Volume Source node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - VEX</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_vex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:45:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_vex/</guid>
      <description>General Partition points Here is a vex version of a techique I saw John Kunz use in Vops. Note that the points comming in on the second input will be the &amp;ldquo;cluster centers&amp;rdquo;. Theese points can be generated anyway you want, for instance by the scatter node or by fusing &amp;ldquo;the original points&amp;rdquo; and with the snap distance control how many centers you want.
Point wrangle
int npt = nearpoint(1, @P);vector p = point(1, &amp;#39;P&amp;#39;, npt);vector relbb = relbbox(0, p);if(relbb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houdini - Misc</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 20:32:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/houdini_misc/</guid>
      <description>A collection of various Houdini related things that doesn´t fit anywhere else.
POP Birth Rate A good way to control the amount of particles being emitted is to keyframe the Const. Birt Rate (Birth tab) with values between 0 and 1. Then we can use the Scale Point Count by Area (Source tab) as a multiplier of points emitted.
Rest attribute If we want to store the position where the particle was spawned we can create a rest attribute to the geo that we use as source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>