<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modelling-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/modelling-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modelling-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:24:47 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/modelling-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Modifiers</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:24:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modifiers/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers General  Here is the Blender modifier docs Apply all modifiers  Object &amp;gt; Convert to &amp;gt; Mesh from Curve/Meta/Surf/Text   Copy Modifiers  Note that we need the Copy Attributes Menu (Interface) add-on installed Select all the objects to copy the modifier to Lastly select the object with the modifiers to copy Ctrl C &amp;gt; Copy Modifiers    Vertex groups  How to create a vertex group  Go into edit mode of the mesh you want to add the group to Click the Object Data Properties Expand the Vertex Groups area Click the + button, and optionally name the group Use the Weights slider (or enter numerically) to specify the weight to be added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender - Modeling</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 16:27:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/blender-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Blender Intro Modelling Modifiers General Gotchas Non-uniform object scale
If an object has non-uniform scale you can run into errors when doing operation on the mesh (edit mode). This is because the object scale is taken into account when the mesh is edited. For instance, we have a cube object with an x-scale of .1 (in object mode) and the verts (in edit mode) are scaled to compensate for this (x-scale 10) resulting in a cube that looks uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>