<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UE5-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/ue5-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UE5-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/ue5-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Sequencer &amp; Movie Render Queue</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-sequencer_and_mrq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-sequencer_and_mrq/</guid>
      <description>Resources Epic  Rendering High Quality Frames with Movie Render Queue  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</guid>
      <description>PBR  Base Color  Real world materials are not darker than 20 srgb or brighter than 240 srgb Rough surfaces have a higher minimun, around 50 srgb Out of range values will not light correctly, so staying in range is critical On a non-metallic material this controls the diffuse  On a metallic material this controls the specular On a metallic material the diffuse is black     Specular  A multiplier for the direct and indirect specular lighting Defining the reflectivity when looking straight at the surface Non-metal surfaces reflects about 4% of the light Specular value:  0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Cinematics</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5_cinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:47:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5_cinematics/</guid>
      <description>Sequencer Tips  Tips  Organize the project using Levels so that multiple people can work on different parts of the project without bottlenecks. Check the streaming state of the levels. Make sure that the levels are streaming (if not you will get a black render) A master sequence, sub-sequence and level sequence is basically the same thing, the difference is how they are used and how they are structured.  A master sequence will contain sub-sequences and level sequences A master sequence is a cointainer of shots   A clean Master sequence  The idea is to keep a master sequence quite clean (and have the complexity such as keyframes, effects etc in sub-sequences) to make it possible for a quick edit at the top level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</guid>
      <description>Settings Configuration files The UE5 docs on configuration files
A tips &amp;amp; tricks video of setting up configuration files
 Invert Middle Mouse Pan
To pan the viewport I like to invert the middle mouse pan.  You can do this on a per project basis using the ui:  Edit &amp;gt; Editor Preferences &amp;gt; Level Editor &amp;gt; Viewports &amp;gt; Invert Middle Mouse Pan : On
Note this will only be set for the project   To invert the middle mouse pan on all new projects  Open the config directory of the engine version you want to edit  The path is something like C:\Program Files\Epic Games\UE_5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>