<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unreal Engine-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal-engine-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unreal Engine-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal-engine-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Landscapes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-landscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-landscapes/</guid>
      <description>Houdini We have created our heightfiled and layers and want to export them.
Heightfield  Heightfield  Note! Since UE is pretty picky with the terrain resolution we might set the Grid Samples to one of the sizes (Division mode is set to By Axis)  8129 4033 2017 1009   For a full list see UE Docs    Export  Export Heightfiled from Houdini to Unreal  Create a COP2 Network and jump in Create a SOP Import node and set the SOP path to the output of the HF  Click  Set resolution from SOP Set planes from SOP Enable remap range     Create a Flip node  Since UE uses a different coordinate system we need to change the data Create a flip node  In the flip tab enable Flop 90 Degrees   Connect the output of the sop import node to the input of the flip node   Create a Convert node  Unreal expects the data to bi in 16 bit so lets convert the data Create a Convert node  Set the Raster Depth to 16 Bit Interger Set the scope to which planes you want to affect or leave at * to convert all     Create a ROP File Output  Set the Valid Frame Range to Current Frame Set the Color Plane to the layer you wish to export (for instance height) Set Alpha Plane to (None) Set the Output Picture Path Note!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Niagara</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-niagara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-niagara/</guid>
      <description>Sprite Smoke A prechewed run-through of the sprite smoke tutorial.
 Sprite Smoke  Note:
This example uses the M_smoke_subUV Material, which can be found with the Starter Content. Create the System and Emitter  Create a folder, name it &amp;ldquo;Niagara_fx&amp;rdquo; (or something else) and step into it. Create a Niagara System, RMB click &amp;gt; FX &amp;gt; Niagara System (or choose from create basic assets at the top of the popup menu) Select New system from selected emitters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 &amp; Houdini</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-houdini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-houdini/</guid>
      <description>Houdini Engine Install  Browse to the SideFX houdini engine dir  SideFX directory  C:\Program Files\Side Effects Software\Houdini Engine\Unreal Here you will find the engine for each of the houdini versions you have installed  19.5.403 19.5.303 etc&amp;hellip;   And inside each houdini version you will find a houdini engine plugin for each of the unreal engine versions.  5.0 4.27     Copy Houdini Engine dir  Find the version that matches your Houdini install and the UE engine Ctrl + C the HoudiniEngine directory     Browse to the Unreal plugin dir  Unreal engine version directory  C:\Program Files\Epic Games\UE_5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Misc</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-misc/</guid>
      <description>Tips Assets  Export UAssets  Select asset(s) in the Content Browser RMB click &amp;gt; Assets Actions &amp;gt; Export or Bulk Export  If we want to export a lot of assets it might be easier to do a bulk export.   Mesh  Select the destination folder The filename will by default be the name of the asset. Export options  LOD : we can choose to include the LODs (or only lod 0 if the Level of Detail is unchecked) Collision &amp;hellip;     Texture  We can export textures as .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Raytraced Lighting</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-raytraced-lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-raytraced-lighting/</guid>
      <description>Settings  Project Settings  Engine &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt;  Global Illumination &amp;gt;  Dynamic Global Illumination Method : Lumen   Reflections &amp;gt;  Reflection Method : Lumen Reflection Capture Resolution : 2048   Lumen &amp;gt;  Use Hardware Raytracing when available : On   Hardware Raytracing &amp;gt;  Support Hardware Raytracing : On  Note! Hardware Ray Tracing requires enabling skin cache. You will be promted to enable skin cache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Lumen</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-lumen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-lumen/</guid>
      <description>Lumen General Info  Surface Cache  Lumen generates an automatic parameterization of the nearby scene surfaces called the Surface Cache It is used to quickly look up lighting at ray hit points in the scene Lumen the captures the material properties for each mesh from multiple angles. These capture positions called cards are generated offline for each mesh   Screen Tracing  Lumen features trace rays against the screen first Before moving on to a more reliable method, if no hit is found or the ray passes behind a surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Movie Render Queue</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-movie-render-queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-movie-render-queue/</guid>
      <description>Movie Render Queue Config Before rendering any sequences loaded in the queue, you will need to configure the settings you want to use. There are a wide variety of settings that can be adjusted, such as output format, filename, and anti-aliasing settings.
 Settings
With the Settings options, you can specify additional configurable items to use when rendering the final output image.  Anti-aliasing  Controls the number of samples and sample types used when rendering out the final images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Python &amp; PySide2</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-python-pyside2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:03:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-python-pyside2/</guid>
      <description>Python plugin Enable the plugins you wish to use. There might be more scripting modules under the scripting tab depending on what you have installed and what you wish to be able to modify with python.
 Edit &amp;gt; Plugins &amp;gt; Scripting &amp;gt;  Editor Scripting Utilities Python Editor Script Plugin Sequencer Scripting etc &amp;hellip;    Developer Mode The developer mode will enable extra warnings eg for deprecated code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</guid>
      <description>How to Translucency &amp;amp; refraction (PBR)  Create a translucent, refractive material in UE 5.2  RMB Content browser &amp;gt; Material In details panel  Material &amp;gt; Blend Mode : Translucent Translucency &amp;gt; Lighting Mode : Surface Translucency Volume Refraction &amp;gt; Refraction Method : Index Of Refraction   Then you can use the common texures or paramers to control the material Note  One big gotcha if you want to use a mesh that you apply an emissive material to to emulate a light source and position that behind the refractive material (like if you create a headlight etc) is that the scale of the mesh needs to be set to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Cinematics</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-cinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:47:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-cinematics/</guid>
      <description>General Tips Camera  Perspective &amp;amp; Camera views  When you are animating a camera it can be nice to use a 2 pane view (cam and persp) setup. Pane setup  3dview (top left corner) &amp;gt; layouts &amp;gt; Two Panes (side by side) Set the cine camera view to use Cinematic Viewport  When a view is set to use the cinematic viewport you get a menu on the top right to set a number of overlays (grid, crosshair, action safe etc)     Cinematic Control  On the pane that you will use as a perspective camera, disable allow cinematic control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</guid>
      <description>Settings Viewports  Level Editor &amp;gt; Viewports  Controls &amp;gt;  Invert Middle Mouse Pan : On Advanced &amp;gt;  Use distance-scaled camera speed : On Orbit camera around selection : On        Configuration files The UE5 docs on configuration files
A tips &amp;amp; tricks video of setting up configuration files
 Invert Middle Mouse Pan
To pan the viewport I like to invert the middle mouse pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Snippets</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:24:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Misc  Enable Input  By default the key input is disabled in the standard template.  This is why we need to enable Input in the BeginPlay event   In a level blueprint we do not need to do this   Consume Keyboard event  By default a keyboard event has the property &amp;ldquo;Consume&amp;rdquo; enabled  if it is enabled it will prevent actors with a lower priority to handle the input     Logic Sequence (Flow Control)  If you want to call n number of functions from one input you can use the &amp;ldquo;Sequence&amp;rdquo; (Flow Control) node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Communication</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-blueprint-communication/</guid>
      <description>Below are som notes from a really good video on blueprint communication by Zak Parrish
Blueprint Communications | Live Training | Unreal Engine
Intro  A way for separate individual obejcts to talk to each other Useful for:  Broadcasting an event to a number of listeners Telling a specfic object to do something Quering another object   UE4 has no way to just &amp;ldquo;send a broad signal to everyone&amp;rdquo;  Trivia: had it in UE2, but it wasn’t very efficient   Communication will always involve the following:  A Sending Blueprint At least one Receiving Blueprint   Communication will always require a reference at some point  The Sender or Receiver has to become aware of the other   All Blueprint communication is 1-way  Blueprints can send data back and forth, but it requires both Blueprints to set up their own individual paths of communication Queries are possible, but are initiated by the Sender (still 1-way)    Types of communication  3 primary Blueprint communication Methods  Direct Communication Blueprint Interface message calls Event Dispatchers    When to use  Flow of communication  Is the sender pushing the data to the reciever?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:53:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>General Tips  System Units  UE uses centimeter (1 UE unit = 1cm)   Copy assets (as text)  If you select some static meshes and Ctrl C you save the selected assets, their translation etc to the clipboard You can then paste the data to a text editor. This data can the be Ctrl V in Unreal editor to &amp;ldquo;replace&amp;rdquo; the actors.   Anti-Aliasing  Project Settings &amp;gt; Engine &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt; Default Settings &amp;gt; Anti-Aliasing Method    Naming Convention Using a good naming convention is important to make the project more efficient to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Getting started</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Below are some notes from Getting Started in Unreal Engine
Install First we click the plus icon and select the version. When we click the install button we get a promt to choose instasll location. Here we can click the options button to choose we we want to include. If we know we are not interested in some of the target platforms we can uncheck them to avoid to have to download and install that data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>