<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unreal Engine-notes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal-engine-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unreal Engine-notes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 22:03:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/unreal-engine-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-materials/</guid>
      <description>PBR  Base Color  Real world materials are not darker than 20 srgb or brighter than 240 srgb Rough surfaces have a higher minimun, around 50 srgb Out of range values will not light correctly, so staying in range is critical On a non-metallic material this controls the diffuse  On a metallic material this controls the specular On a metallic material the diffuse is black     Specular  A multiplier for the direct and indirect specular lighting Defining the reflectivity when looking straight at the surface Non-metal surfaces reflects about 4% of the light Specular value:  0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Cinematics</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5_cinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:47:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5_cinematics/</guid>
      <description>Sequencer Tips This is a good lecture on sequencer.
 Tips  Organize the project using Levels so that multiple people can work on different parts of the project without bottlenecks. Check the streaming state of the levels. Make sure that the levels are streaming (if not you will get a black render) A master sequence, sub-sequence and level sequence is basically the same thing, the difference is how they are used and how they are structured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-notes/</guid>
      <description>Viewport  Get mouse control when game plays : Shift F1  Camera  Toggle exact camera view  Ctrl + Shift + C    Navigation  Perspective view:  Alt + G Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; south east / west Ctrl + MMB click -&amp;gt; menu   Front view  Alt + H Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; east   Back view  Alt + Shift + H Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; west   Top view  Alt + J Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; north   Bottom view  Alt + Shift + J Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; south   Left view  Alt + K Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; north east   Right view  Alt + Shift + K Ctrl + MMB -&amp;gt; north west    Manipulation  Toggle the manipulator  Space bar    Pivot  Set pivot of selected  With the object selected hold Alt + MMB click on an surface to where you want to set your pivot LMB click on the object to reset    Content Browser  Toggle content browser : Ctrl Space Show Content browser folder in Explorer : RMB click &amp;gt; Show in Explorer Seems like the DDC has moved to inside the project structure?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Snippets</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:24:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_snippets/</guid>
      <description>Misc  Enable Input  By default the key input is disabled in the standard template.  This is why we need to enable Input in the BeginPlay event   In a level blueprint we do not need to do this   Consume Keyboard event  By default a keyboard event has the property &amp;ldquo;Consume&amp;rdquo; enabled  if it is enabled it will prevent actors with a lower priority to handle the input     Logic Sequence (Flow Control)  If you want to call n number of functions from one input you can use the &amp;ldquo;Sequence&amp;rdquo; (Flow Control) node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Blueprint Communication</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_blueprint_communication/</guid>
      <description>Below are som notes from a really good video on blueprint communication by Zak Parrish
Blueprint Communications | Live Training | Unreal Engine
Intro  A way for separate individual obejcts to talk to each other Useful for:  Broadcasting an event to a number of listeners Telling a specfic object to do something Quering another object   UE4 has no way to just &amp;ldquo;send a broad signal to everyone&amp;rdquo;  Trivia: had it in UE2, but it wasn’t very efficient   Communication will always involve the following:  A Sending Blueprint At least one Receiving Blueprint   Communication will always require a reference at some point  The Sender or Receiver has to become aware of the other   All Blueprint communication is 1-way  Blueprints can send data back and forth, but it requires both Blueprints to set up their own individual paths of communication Queries are possible, but are initiated by the Sender (still 1-way)    Types of communication  3 primary Blueprint communication Methods  Direct Communication Blueprint Interface message calls Event Dispatchers    When to use  Flow of communication  Is the sender pushing the data to the reciever?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:53:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>General Tips  System Units  UE uses centimeter (1 UE unit = 1cm)   Copy assets (as text)  If you select some static meshes and Ctrl C you save the selected assets, their translation etc to the clipboard You can then paste the data to a text editor. This data can the be Ctrl V in Unreal editor to &amp;ldquo;replace&amp;rdquo; the actors.   Anti-Aliasing  Project Settings &amp;gt; Engine &amp;gt; Rendering &amp;gt; Default Settings &amp;gt; Anti-Aliasing Method    Naming Convention Using a good naming convention is important to make the project more efficient to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Getting started</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue4_getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Below are some notes from Getting Started in Unreal Engine
Install First we click the plus icon and select the version. When we click the install button we get a promt to choose instasll location. Here we can click the options button to choose we we want to include. If we know we are not interested in some of the target platforms we can uncheck them to avoid to have to download and install that data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UE4 - Python / PySide2</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/unreal_python_pyside2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 15:03:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/unreal_python_pyside2/</guid>
      <description>Enable Python Enable the plugins you wish to use. There might be more scripting modules under the scripting tab depending on what you have installed and what you wish to be able to modify with python.
 Edit &amp;gt; Plugins &amp;gt; Scripting &amp;gt;  Python Editor Script Plugin : Enable    Optionally we can also enable developer mode (on a per project basis). This will wnable extra warnings eg for deprecated code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>