<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landscapes on Petfactory</title>
    <link>https://www.petfactory.se/tags/landscapes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Landscapes on Petfactory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.petfactory.se/tags/landscapes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UE5 - Landscapes</title>
      <link>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-landscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petfactory.se/notes/ue5-landscapes/</guid>
      <description>Houdini We have created our heightfiled and layers and want to export them.
Heightfield  Heightfield  Note! Since UE is pretty picky with the terrain resolution we might set the Grid Samples to one of the sizes (Division mode is set to By Axis)  8129 4033 2017 1009   For a full list see UE Docs    Export  Export Heightfiled from Houdini to Unreal  Create a COP2 Network and jump in Create a SOP Import node and set the SOP path to the output of the HF  Click  Set resolution from SOP Set planes from SOP Enable remap range     Create a Flip node  Since UE uses a different coordinate system we need to change the data Create a flip node  In the flip tab enable Flop 90 Degrees   Connect the output of the sop import node to the input of the flip node   Create a Convert node  Unreal expects the data to be in 16 bit so lets convert the data Create a Convert node  Set the Raster Depth to 16 Bit Interger Set the scope to which planes you want to affect or leave at * to convert all If we do not do this you will see some &amp;ldquo;stepping&amp;rdquo; artifacts in the hf in unreal     Create a ROP File Output  Set the Valid Frame Range to Current Frame Set the Color Plane to the layer you wish to export (for instance height) Set Alpha Plane to (None) Disable Convert to Image Format&amp;rsquo;s Colorspace  We do not want a gamma curve applied to the height data so lets turn off Convert to Image Format&amp;rsquo;s Colorspace If we do not turn this off the gamma curve will be baked into the heightfield, meaning the height data will be &amp;ldquo;transformed&amp;rdquo; by the gamma.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>